Register of the George I. Duca Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1819-1985 (Box 101)
  - Romania (Box 103)
    - History. Real estate documents belonging to several Romanian boyards, 1819-1845 (Folder 103: 1)
    - Politics and government, 1918-1989.
      Clippings
      - General (Folder 103: 2)
      - Hohenzollern family (Folder 103: 3)
  - Miscellany (Folder 103: 4-5)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1890-1985 (Box 104)
  - 1 print depicting George Duca as a child (Folder 104: 1)
  - 3 prints depicting George Duca's visit to (?) Newport, R. I., 1930 (Folder 104: 2)
  - 2 prints depicting George Duca's visit to Saloniki, Greece, 1932 (Folder 104: 3)
  - Album of prints of Ion G. Duca's visit to Blaj, 1925 (Folder 104: 4)
  - 56 prints depicting Marie, Queen of Romania, and Ileana, Princess of Romania, visiting the Duca estate at Maldaresti, 1922, 1926 (Folder 104: 5)
  - 4 prints depicting Marie, Queen of Romania, visiting the United States, 1926 (Folder 104: 6)
  - 1 print depicting Marie, Queen of Romania, with Prince and Princess Bibesco (Folder 104: 7)
  - Album of prints on Marie, Queen of Romania, 1933 (Folder 104: 8)
  - 12 prints depicting Marie, Queen of Romania's funeral, 1938 (Folder 104: 9)
  - 7 prints depicting members of the Romanian royal family, including Carol I, King of Romania; Elisabeta, Queen Consort of Carol I of Romania; Ferdinand, King of Romania; Carol II, King of Romania, 1880-1944 (Box-folder 105: 1)
  - 6 prints depicting members of the Romanian royal family (Folder 105: 2)
  - 12 prints depicting Marie, Queen, Consort of King Ferdinand of Romania, 1914-1938 (Folder 105: 3)
  - 10 prints depicting Marie, Queen, Consort of King Ferdinand of Romania, 1914-1938, as well as Elizabeth, Queen, Consort of George II, King of Greece, and Maria, Queen, Consort of Alexander I of Yugoslavia (Folder 105: 4)
  - 1 print depicting Marie, Queen, Consort of King Ferdinand of Romania, 1914-1938 (Folder 105: 5)
  - 5 prints depicting Marie, Queen, Consort of King Ferdinand of Romania, 1914-1938, as well as Michael, King of Romania (Folder 105: 6)
  - 10 prints depicting Marie, Queen, Consort of King Ferdinand of Romania, 1914-1938, as well as Michael, King of Romania (Folder 105: 7)
  - 9 prints depicting Marie, Queen, Consort of King Ferdinand of Romania, 1914-1938, as well as Nicolai, Prince of Romania (Folder 105: 8)
  - 10 prints depicting Marie, Queen, Consort of King Ferdinand of Romania, 1914-1938 (Folder 105: 9)
  - 5 prints depicting Marie, Queen, Consort of King Ferdinand of Romania, 1914-1938 (Folder 105: 10)
  - 8 prints depicting Ileana, Princess of Romania, 1910-1985 (Folder 105: 11)
  - 20 prints depicting Ileana, Princess of Romania, 1910-1985 (Folder 105: 12)
  - 16 prints depicting Ileana, Princess of Romania, 1910-1985 (Folder 105: 13)
  - 19 prints depicting Ileana, Princess of Romania, 1910-1985 (Folder 105: 14)
  - 6 prints depicting Helen, Queen, Consort of Carol II of Romania, 1926-? (Folder 105: 15)
  - 9 prints depicting miscellaneous people related to the Romanian royal family, n.d. (Folder 105: 16)
  - 8 prints depicting miscellaneous others related to the Romanian royal family, n.d. (Folder 105: 17)
  - 12 prints depicting miscellaneous others related to the Romanian royal family, n.d. (Folder 105: 18)
  - 12 prints depicting festivities celebrating the tenth anniversary of the union with Transylvania, 1929. (Folder 105: 19)
    Includes prints of Michael I, King of Romania, Queen Helen, and Juliu Maniu
  - 2 prints depicting official occasions, 1923-1925. (Folder 105: 20)
    Includes prints of Carol II, King of Romania
  - 2 prints depicting Royal occasions, 1930-1931 (Folder 105: 21)
  - 60 loose prints from George Duca's diaries. (Box-folder 106: 1)
    Includes prints of the Romanian royal family, Ion G. Duca, Georges Enescu, Stirbey and Duca families, and Jean Negulesco
  - Negatives covering the years 1914-1947 (except for 1940, 1947-1966, 1968-1976) (Box 107)
  - 14 prints depicting members of the Romanian royal family (oversize) (Box-folder 108: 1)
  - 1 poster size print of George Duca, 1985 (Photo-file envelope mA)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS, 1819-1934 (Box 109)
  - Drawings
    - Of Duca's estate of Maldaresti and of Ion G. Duca's grave in Ursani (Folder 109: 1)
    - Of Queen Helen's estate from San Domenico de Fiesole, by Queen Ana, consort of Michael, King of Romania (Folder 109: 2)
  - Newspaper issues covering some of the main events in Romanian history (mainly related to the royal family and Ion G. Duca), 1896-1934 (Folder 109: 3)
  - Real estate document belonging to one Romanian boyard, 1845 (Folder 109: 4)
- PHONOTAPES, 1961-1971 (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
  - "Le petit concert d'adieu pour Monsieur Duca chez Monsieur et Madame Matouyama," 1961 June 24 (Tape-cabinet 1-2)
  - Interview of George Duca for Radio Free Europe, 1971 April 18 (Tape-cabinet 3)
  - "Global Conversation: The Role of Cultural Organizations in International Affairs," 1967 January 1. Guest: George Duca; panelists: Dr. Michael Flack and Dr. Monique Lewis (Tape-cabinet 4)